Timur Badretdinov

Android Developer

+7(999)-169-26-84 | tim_baton@mail.ru | linkedin.com/in/timur-badretdinov

SUMMARY

Android developer with more than 5 years of experience. Right now besides developing mobile applications I'm interested in product management and leading processes. I am comfortable wearing many hats and have both full-time and hobby experience in software engineering. In my spare time, I have developed a small app for dog owners, which has been written about by about a dozen Russian publishers. My primary focus has been on native Android development, but I have also worked with Flutter (about a year) to develop cross-platformed applications.

EXPERIENCE

Lead Android Developer

December 2020 - Present

VTB, Admiral

Remote

- Created a component library for the one of the top-3 banks in Russia, now the library is being used by 10+ teams in the bank
- Built a flexible workflow of communicating with other teams so that we can develop our library due to the needs of the other teams and our vision
- Created golang scripts to download and update fonts, themes and icons from the Figma project. This has reduced the theme update time from hours to minutes
- Together with the team, we launched our own podcast channel about mobile development

VTB, Sfera

- Redesigned the multi-module-clean architecture, which improved compilation time by 15%
- Created and maintained development process for a platform team of six people
- Designed, developed and launched several demo apps for different teams to speed up the development process, which accelerated the compilation up to 3 times

Android Developer

May 2020 – December 2020

Lifehacker

Remote

- Led a three-person distributed development team that created an application with a lifehack feed that includes chat, comments, complex feed screens and that support offline mode, notifications and heavy background tasks
- Reduced the release time by configuring the testing flow and implementing ci/cd via Firebase
- Developed the app from scratch and uploaded it to the Play Market

Android Developer

June 2019 - May 2020

Recan

Remote

- Designed and configured multi-module architecture for the whole project
- Fixed some security issues, eg turned off logging in production builds
- Developed the app from scratch and uploaded it to the Play Market

Android Developer

January 2018 - June 2019

Super Eqo

Remote

- Integrated an offline mode for core screens
- Decreased size of application for 5 times (from 76 Mb to 14 Mb) using Gradle flavors and optimizations
- Improved development process in the company: introduced unit testing, CI and static analysis, Clean architecture with MVP
- Developed more than 30 new screens using Material guidelines

EDUCATION

Kazan Federal University

Kazan, Russia